### Mohamed Abdulaziz

♦ ANKARA, TURKEY

## **∸** Profile

I am software engineering graduate student with experience working in the medical and consultancy sector. I am currently pursuing a graduate degree in Software Engineering at Atılım University with a focus on artificial intelligence and blockchain technologies.

# Employment history

Full-stack developer for Savannah Pharmaceutical Co.

May 2017 - March 2018

I built an inventory and sales management system using Python, Flask and MySQL that stored medical supplier information, tracked status of orders, managed warehouse inventory levels, and generated reports on demand. This resulted in a 20% increase in item fill order, 15% decrease in cycle time and a 10% increase gross margin over the last two quarters.

Junior Tendering Engineer at MGS Project Consultancy Engineering Trade Limited Co., Ankara

December 2016 - April 2017

Responsible for discovering various public and private tenders. Enhanced the company's online presence through the creation of a company storefront on multiple platforms.

#### Education

Atılım University, Ankara

Degree expected: 2019

**Degree: Masters in Software Engineering** 

Middle East Technical University, Ankara

February 2017

Degree: Bachelor in Aerospace Engineering

## Projects

char-rnn: A deep learning text generator

June 2018 - Present

A text generator using a multi-layer recurrent neural network in Python using Keras. I created a web API for users to generate their own texts using Flask via a webpage.

lstm-electric-load-forecast

May 2018 - June 2018

Forecast power consumption of a household data taken over almost 4 years using a long-short-term-memory neural network.

AIAA Design/Build/Fly, Wichita, Kansas

October 2015 - April 2016

Developed a machine learning airfoil optimization software using Python which resulted in a 15% increase in aircraft performance.

### Certification

ISTQB Certified Tester Foundation Level

May 2018

Python Programming, Wesleyan University (MOOC)

June 2017

Commercial Drone Pilot Certification (IHA1)

April 2017

GRE Math Score: 167/170 (top 1%)
GRE Verbal Score: 168/170 (top 1%)
TOEFL Test Scores: 117/120 (top 1%)

Details

Toki Incek Konutlari Alacaatlı-İncek Yolu, Ankara, Turkey +90 5060559422 mo.hassaniv@gmail.com https://demmojo.github.io/

Skills

Python

MySQL

MATLAB

C++

Flask

Simulink

Java

Microsoft Office Suite

Languages

English (TOEFL 117/120)

Arabic

Somali

Turkish